AALIYAH MOTALA

DATA ANALYST

Contact

+27 83 667 6639

aaliyahmotala@gmail.com

LinkedIn

<u>GitHub</u>

Skills

Python

SQL

R Software

Tableau

HTML

Problem-solving

Communication

Project Management

Leadership and Teamwork

Research

Languages

English

• • • • •

Afrikaans

• • • •

Chinese

Hobbies

Gaming Reading books Learning languages

Summary

Passionate data analyst that is adept at analyzing data from multiple data mediums such as Access, SQL, and Python. Bringing forth the ability to visualize information with Excel and Tableau. Experienced in preparing detailed documents and reports as well as interacting effectively with colleagues and clients

Education

Data Analyst Nanodegree

ALX-Udacity | August 2022 - October 2022

BSc Biological Science Honours

University of KwaZulu-Natal | Feb 2014 - Apr 2019

Courses

Data Analyst - Excel & Tableau

EntryLevel | June 2022 - July 2022

Data Analyst - SQL

EntryLevel | July 2022 - August 2022

Data Analyst - Advanced SQL

EntryLevel | August 2022 - Present

Work Experience

Clinical Trial Recruiter

Subjectwell | August 2021 - December 2021

Research Assistant

University of KwaZulu-Natal | May 2021 - August 2021

- Undertook and planned fieldwork
- Created a database of findings
- Created a GIS layer using Google Earth
- Analyzed findings with R software

Laboratory Demonstrator

University of KwaZulu-Natal|March 2021 - July 2021

Intern

South African National Biodiversity Institute | June 2019 - March 2021

- Presented at the <u>Conservation Symposium 2019</u>
- Project managed the CREW workshop 2019
- Provided over 10 training sessions of iNaturalist software to various age groups at universities and workshop
- Managed, analyzed and provided report of the divisions database
- Published an article for Leopard Echo: <u>Citizen Science</u>: <u>History, games</u> and <u>lockdown</u>